5 guys. 4 legends. 3 lovers. 2 friends. 1 band.
Backbeat is a drama, music film directed by Iain Softley.
Chronicles the early days of The Beatles in Hamburg, Germany.
The film focuses primarily on the relationship between Stuart Sutcliffe,
John Lennon, and Sutcliffe's girlfriend Astrid Kirchherr.
Stuart Sutcliffe, played by Stephen Dorff.
John Lennon, played by Ian Hart.
Astrid Kirchherr, played by Sheryl Lee.
Paul McCartney, played by Gary Bakewell.
George Harrison, played by Chris O'Neill.
Pete Best, played by Scot Williams.
Backbeat is a 1994 British biographical drama film directed and
co-written by Iain Softley in his feature directorial debut.
It chronicles the early days of the Beatles in Hamburg, West Germany, focusing primarily on the relationship between Stuart Sutcliffe
(Stephen Dorff) and John Lennon (Ian Hart), and also with Sutcliffe's German girlfriend Astrid Kirchherr (Sheryl Lee).
The film was produced by Channel Four Films and PolyGram Filmed
Entertainment, and was released in the UK on 1 April 1994.
It received mixed-to-positive reviews from critics, though was
well-received by the real-life Beatles and Kirchherr.
The score by Don Was earned a BAFTA Award for Best Original Music, and the
film was nominated for Outstanding British Film and Best Sound.
The film explores themes of guitar, red-light district, stuart
sutcliffe, boyfriend girlfriend relationship, river elbe.
The tone is emotional.